

💌 andrewalford1@outlook.com | 🏕 andrewalford1.github.io/me/ | 🖸 andrewalford1 | 🛅 andrew-alford-479155152

# Summary\_

I'm a junior Software Engineer from the UK specialising in both games development (through my degree) and programming for the web (through my own interests). My goals are to constantly be improving my quality of code and to work within industry on new projects with exciting technologies.

# **Education**

## **BSC (HONS) Computer Science with Games Development**

NORTHUMBRIA UNIVERSITY NEWCASTLE

Sept 2016 - July 2019

- Expected to be a First Class Degree
- All grades range from 70% to 100%

## **Other Qualifications**

A-Levels & GCSEs Sept 2012 - July 2016

- A-Level Computer Science: Grade B
- A-Level Mathematics: Grade B
- A-Level Design & Technology: Grade B
- Nine GCSEs including Mathematics, English, & Science

# Skills

Languages JavaScript, C#, C++, Java, Python

**Libraries & APIs** React, THREE JS, CANNON JS, OpenGL, DirectX

**Software & Tools** VS Code & Visual Studio, Eclipse, Overleaf, The Adobe Suite

# **Projects**

CHRISTMAS CONLINDRUM

MIDNIGHT RISING

C++ & Unreal Engine 4 Northumbria University

NO REST FOR THE MARTIANS May 2017

- A game created using C++ & Unreal Engine 4 in which a human survivor fight against Mars' oppressive robot overlords
- · In-game models visually change state and eventually explode as a result of damage caused by the player
- · C++ has been used to script functional doors which open/close in response to the player's actions within the game
- C++ has been used to create reusable and customisable 'pick-up' items which affect the player's stats

## JavaScript, THREE JS, & Virtual Reality

Northumbria University

GALAXY ADVENTURE December 2018

- · Using JavaScript and the THREE JS library, this project allows users to view a low-poly animated galaxy through a VR headset
- Particle effects such as lava exploding from volcanoes was implemented for this project
- · Planets orbit around the sun and each other all at various speeds

C++ & DirectX Northumbria University

December 2018

- This is a demonstration of modifications made to Northumbria University's Shell Engine
- · A component based architecture was implemented to keep classes lowly coupled and highly cohesive
- Sprite sheets that can be animated in various directions and speeds were implemented
- · Collision detection between game entities was also implemented

**C# & Unity Engine** Northumbria University

May 2019

- A top-down twin-stick shooter game where players must survive waves of enemy zombies
- · Zombies become increasingly difficult over time through modifying their stats dependant on the wave number
- · Zombies will dynamically spawn nearby the player outside the camera's frustum to maintain the games intensity
- The game is support for both PC & Xbox One peripherals

Crazy Carnival May 2019

- In this application players can participate in multiple carnival games using a Microsoft Kinect
- Gesture tracking controls the player's movements in the game world as well as interactive elements in the game such as firing cannon balls and setting off fireworks
- Models are loaded into the scene dynamically using both JSON and JavaScript
- CANNON JS is used to simulate real-time physics for throwing bowling balls and kicking footballs

## C#, Unity Engine, & WebGL

Northumbria University

CPU ONLINE

May 2019

- My Undergraduate dissertation
- Using modern technology, CPU Online is a re-imagining of JASPer, a CPU simulator used to teach University students the fundamentals of computer science
- Registers, memory, and buses are animated and fully interactive
- It includes a text editor so programs can be written, assembled, and loaded into memory
- A console, GUI, and a clock have been included for interacting with the simulator to play/pause, speed up, slow down, or step through the
  execution of programs

# **Extracurricular Activity**

## **Northumbria University Newcastle**

STUDENT VOLUNTEER

- Treasurer of the Ouseburn Farm charity society
- · Secretary of the Ad-Hoc society
- Community Week captain for 2017/18

#### Nissan

THIRD PLACE WINNER OF THE NISSAN TECH CHALLENGE

April 2018

Sept 2016 - July 2019

· A technical and physical challenge held between many Universities from the North East

# **Experience**

Northern Football Club Gosforth

Bar Staff Jan 2016 - PRESENT

McDonnalds Newcastle

 CREW MEMBER
 Aug 2014 - Aug 2015

## References

## Organisation

Јони Дое

- Email: emailaddress@outlook.com
- Phone: 07000000000

#### **Northern Football Club**

DAVID GILES - GENERAL MANAGER

- Email: davidgiles@northernfootballclub.co.uk
- Phone: +441912363369